( baby cooing )
( people whispering indistinctly )
( dramatic music playing )
Woman : Mam ?
Mam !
Ma !
( dog barking )
( dramatic music playing )
( baby crying )
( grunts )
Char : Granny ?
Why didn 't you wake me up , I 'm late .
Oh , sorry , love .
- Can I get a lift , please ? - Did you get any breakfast ?
Take this for your lunch . There .
- Can I get a lift , please ? - Ah , I can 't drive today .
My foot has seized up with the change in the weather .
Could you grab me a towel there ?
Char : I 've missed the bus . What do I do ?
Why don 't you ask your mother ?
It 'll get her out of bed .
Char : Mam ?
I 'm late for school and Granny can 't give me a lift .
Angela : What ?
Never mind .
- I can walk . - No . No , no , no , no . I 'll ...
I 'll bring you in , okay ? I 'm just ...
Just give me a minute , yeah ?
Char : I 'm just going to go wait in the car .
Are you going to work today ?
No .
Is everything okay ?
I 'm just tired .
Could you go to the shops after you drop me to school ?
Why ?
What do we need ?
Char : I don 't know . Like , bread ,
cereal , milk , everything .
I need ... I need to get home .
Mam , we need food in the house .
Mam , are you listening to me ?
Mam !
Mam ! Mam !
- ( eerie music playing ) - ( horse snorts )
( Char inhales sharply )
( snorts )
What are you doing ?
Mam , what is wrong with you ?
( sighs )
I 'm ...
- Char , I 'm sorry ... - It 's fine .
( car door opens )
I don 't think I can do this anymore .
Char : What ?
I can 't do this anymore .
Go home , then .
- ( dramatic music playing ) - ( children clamoring )
( sighs )
( indistinct chatter )
Hey , Char .
Can you take a seat for me there ? Quick .
So , today I am returning your essays to you , girls .
- Suzanne ? - Suzanne : What , Miss ?
Ms. Devlin : And I have to say it .
The results were disappointing .
It was all in the notes I gave you .
Really , all you had to do was read them .
Student : All you had to do was read it .
- Ms. Devlin : Thanks . - Suzanne : It 's easy as that .
Ms. Devlin : There was one essay ,
which seemed to cover all the marks .
So , I 've printed it off as an example
of how to answer the exam question .
Good job , Char .
( Suzanne chuckles )
Ms. Devlin : Suzanne , move .
- Now . - ( Suzanne chuckling )
Suzanne : Miss , I swear , you fancy me .
Ms. Devlin : Next to Char there , come on !
And will you lose the chewing gum , please ?
You need some chewing gum , Miss .
Ms. Devlin : Rude .
( sighs )
Ms. Devlin : Now , last week we looked
at techniques and interpretation .
Today , we 're going to do some work
on pre-Christian stone carving
ahead of our field trip this week .
This will come up on the exam ,
so please take down notes for me , okay ?
We will look at each section ...
( paper crinkles )
( dramatic music playing )
Ms. Devlin : And don 't forget I need your permission slips
signed for our trip this week . No slip , no trip . Okay ?
You 'll be sent to study for the day .
- Girl : Ah , Miss . - Ah , yeah .
( students giggle )
Ms. Devlin : Be good .
Char : This is my 2D .
Ms. Devlin : Thank you .
( melancholic music playing )
Ms. Devlin : Where did you get the idea for that ?
It was in a dream I had .
Ms. Devlin : How 're you getting on ?
Good .
Ms. Devlin : I mean , academically you 're doing great .
Skipping ahead a year can be tough .
You still get to see your old friends at lunch , right ?
Yeah .
( students speaking indistinctly )
( soft music playing )
( birds chirping )
( indistinct chatter )
( birds cawing )
( eerie music playing )
Officer : When did you last hear from her ?
Rita : She left to bring her to school .
And then didn 't come back here after .
Officer : Uh , she dropped you at your school ?
Char .
At Brigid 's .
Officer : When your mum dropped you off ,
did she say where she was going after that ?
No .
Uh , how was the drive to school ?
Was she all right ?
She said she was tired .
- ( footsteps approaching ) - ( door closing )
Hey , any word from her ?
Officer : Who is this ?
- My son . - ( exhales sharply )
Well , I was just saying to your mum there
that there is not much we can do right now ,
as it 's only been a few hours .
Aaron : Her car door was wide open .
You don 't think that 's a bit fuckin ' weird ?
What , she left her car in the middle of a field
and went for a stroll ?
What about CCTV ?
Officer : We haven 't checked yet ,
but this area isn 't the most well-covered .
Yeah , big fucking surprise .
Do you have anyone out there looking for her ?
Officer : I 've notified the cars that are out there ,
but in the lead in to Halloween , we got a lot of calls coming in .
Aaron : A few teenagers setting up some bonfire
is more important than a missing person ?
( scoffing )
Like , what if someone took her from the car ?
And ... and brought her down . There 's loads of laneways ...
Aaron !
She was in one of her down moods .
Officer : She 's done this before ?
Not in a long time .
Officer : Has she ever gone missing before ?
Char , um , will you go up and just try find
a couple of photos of her ?
You know , we can go out and see if anyone 's seen her later .
( door closing )
( muffled chattering )
( melancholic music playing )
Aaron : We need recent ones . Does your mum not have
an album or something upstairs in her room ?
Char : I didn 't look there .
Aaron : All right , um ...
You head down to the green ,
I 'll head up towards the village .
Just ask around and see if anyone saw her .
Are you all right ?
She said something in the car today .
Aaron : What did she say ?
She said , " I can 't do this anymore . "
( dramatic music playing )
( chuckles )
Uh , she 'll probably be home before we get back here anyway ,
you know ? ( chuckles )
Yeah .
( distant police siren blaring )
( kids speaking indistinctly )
Hey !
- Hey , where you going ? - Char : Just going home .
Suzanne : You weren 't running off to tell anyone
we were putting pallets there , were you ?
No .
I don 't know if I trust her .
( kids chuckling )
What did you see ?
You were just getting stuff for the bonfire .
Mm , wrong .
- You didn 't see anything . - ( chuckles )
And you 'll be telling anyone that asked that , yeah ?
Is this your mam ?
( chuckles )
- Kelly : What the fuck ? - Amanda : That is fuckin ' weird .
Can I get that back , please ?
Suzanne : I know , I know , I know .
You have a drag of this and you don 't cough ,
and you get the photo back .
Fair enough .
( chuckles )
- Amanda : Oh ! - ( Suzanne chuckling )
- Kelly : Oh , is she gonna do it ? - Amanda : Oh !
- Kelly : Oh ! - Amanda : Oh !
- ( coughs ) - ( all chuckle )
Kelly : That 's actually too bad .
Char : No , stop !
( all chuckle )
( birds chirping )
Suzanne : What ?
( dramatic music playing )
Please come back .
Aaron : Char !
That 's it . It 's over .
My life is over .
May as well just throw myself off a bridge .
Woman on TV : What is it now ?
Kid on TV : Promise me you won 't be mad ?
Woman on TV : Katrina .
( TV continues indistinctly )
Aaron : How many do you usually take ?
Rita : Two , or I won 't sleep .
( Aaron sighs )
Aaron : Right , I better head off .
I have to be on the site early tomorrow .
Will you be okay ?
We 'll be fine .
Aaron : Right , well let me know if you hear of anything .
Of course .
' Night , Aaron .
I made you something .
- Char : What is it ? - It 's for protection .
It will keep you safe .
Thanks , Granny .
- You should get some sleep . - Yeah .
I 'm just going to finish this episode .
All right .
Don 't stay up too late .
Rita : Your mother will come back , Char .
She 'll come back .
Woman on TV : Well , I know so .
I love you no matter what . And I think you are magical .
- Thanks , Mum . - ( tense music playing )
( floorboard creaking )
Woman on TV : Do you want to help me carve this pumpkin ?
Kid on TV : Ugh , I don 't really want to get my hands dirty .
( laughter on TV )
Woman on TV : I think they taste delicious .
Kid on TV : No .
Char : Ew , it 's gross .
Angela : Aw .
- You don 't like brains ? - No .
Are you sure you don 't like brains ?
Char , are you hungry ?
- I think you 'd like brains . - No .
- I think you 're hungry . - No .
Ah , go on ! Oh , my God , look at this .
- Oh , it 's delicious ! - ( laughs )
( laughs ) Nam , nam , nam !
Angela : I got ya . Wait a minute now .
Come here , they 're delicious .
( Young Char laughing )
( tense music playing )
( inaudible scream )
( retches )
( clattering )
( wind howling )
( suspenseful music playing )
Mam ?
( door opening , closing )
( door closing )
Aaron : Hey .
Get your ma a glass of water , will you ?
Is she okay ?
Aaron : Yeah , she 's all right .
Got you that .
The doctor gave her something ,
so she might be a little funny for a while .
Does she have to take them as well ?
Aaron : Yeah .
Is she sick ?
Aaron : Fuck !
I forgot one of the prescriptions .
I need to get to work . For fuck 's sake .
Char : I could just go get it , if you want ?
Aaron : Are you sure ?
It 's that one there , um , lithium .
They probably have it there , they just forgot
to put it in the bag .
Aaron : I have to head off now ,
but Char has taken today off school ,
so she can go out and get the rest of your meds .
Rita : And I 'll be here with you too .
Aaron : I did a bit of a shop there as well ...
( telephone ringing )
Pharmacist : What was the name again ?
Um , it was for Angela Delaney .
Hey .
Suzanne : Hey .
You know , I ... I heard about your mam .
Is she all right ?
Yesterday , when ...
I didn 't know you were out looking for her , okay ?
You know , you can call me a dickhead ,
- punch me in the face , or ... - Why do you care ?
I don 't .
Okay , then , can you just leave me alone , please ?
Suit yourself .
Frank : Who 's that ?
A girl from school .
Delaney ?
Suzanne : Yeah . Why ?
Frank : I don 't want you talking to her .
Suzanne : Why ?
Frank : I said , I don 't want you talking to her .
( dramatic music playing )
Where 's Mam ?
She 's having a lie-down , upstairs .
Where are you going ?
Rita : I have to meet a friend about your mother .
I won 't be long .
( suspenseful music playing )
( clattering )
( pop music playing over radio )
( hums )
Char : Mam ?
Hey .
- ( chuckles ) - What are you wearing ?
It 's a dress .
- You don 't like it ? - No , I do .
Are you making dinner ?
Yeah .
You used the pumpkin .
Aaron got us that to carve for Halloween .
Angela : Oh , um .
Char : No , no . It 's fine . It 's fine .
How 're you feeling ?
I 'm good .
Do you know what ? I 'm ... I 'm great . ( chuckles )
♪ Oh , me , oh , my You make me sigh ♪
♪ You 're such A good looking woman ♪
♪ When people stop And people stare ♪
♪ You know It fills my heart ... ♪
( chuckles ) What are you doing ?
( snaps fingers ) Dancing .
You know ? Why don 't you have a dance ?
- Mam , stop . - Come on .
You want to shake it ? No .
- Go on . - What are you doing ? Stop .
Do that , um , that twirl thing . Yeah , push . Like , out . ( grunts )
( chuckles ) Do it again , go on .
- ( whoops , chuckles ) - ( giggles )
( door closing )
♪ The most incredible angel They had ♪
♪ Was found to be Quite unable ... ♪
Do you want to go set the table ?
Dinner will be ready soon .
Rita : Smells nice .
( exclaims )
Rita : Sorry , love .
Aaron : Hello ?
Uh , something smells nice . Didn 't know you were cooking .
Lucky I brought chips .
Are you not eating ?
Aaron : The front door isn 't closing properly .
Needs a new latch , I think .
I can call tomorrow and fix it .
Those pills mess with your appetite .
How long do you have to take them for ?
She 'll take them as long as she needs to take them , Mam .
Are you going to school tomorrow , Char ?
- Yeah , I guess so . - Uh , she doesn 't have to .
You don 't have to , if you don 't want .
Actually , I 've a permission slip I need you to sign .
Has to be in by tomorrow , so ...
- Aaron : Are you going on a trip ? - Char : mm-hmm .
We 're going to this heritage site .
And then we 're off on our midterm break
for Halloween .
Aaron : I 'd love to be going on a mid-term right about now ,
to be honest .
I think we should go away on your break .
Just the two of us .
Like , where ?
I don 't know .
Wherever we want .
Aaron : Do you not think you should , uh ,
stay home and take it easy at the moment ?
Uh , I think a break away would be the perfect rest .
Aaron : Yeah , but remember what the doctor said ,
just to try and keep a healthy routine for a while .
I think it 'd be fun if we got in the car ,
and we didn 't know where we were going ...
Aaron : You 're not going away for the weekend !
- Aaron : Hey . - Char : Hey .
- Aaron : You okay ? - Yeah .
Here , I need to give you something .
What is this ?
Aaron : It 's your mam 's bank card .
I just don 't want her going anywhere , or ...
I just want you to keep it safe , all right ?
We ... we all just need to work together right now .
Just make sure she 'll get better , yeah ?
Char : Yeah .
( clattering )
( Angela breathing erratically )
( Angela gasps )
( tense music playing )
( Angela groaning )
( gasps , moans )
( inhales )
( retches , spits )
( Angela pants )
( breathing shakily )
- ( footsteps approaching ) - ( door opening )
Angela : ( whispers ) Are you awake ?
- Are you awake ? - ( students chattering )
Ms. Devlin : Now , just set them down over there for me .
Char : I meant to give you this .
Thank you .
Who signed that for you ?
My mam .
How is your mam ?
Char : She 's fine .
Must 've been scary for you ...
when she went missing ?
What do you mean ? She wasn 't missing .
Look , I know it 's not easy ...
when our parents aren 't well .
She 's not sick .
Okay .
I have to go home .
Ms. Devlin : My door is always open for you .
If you ever just want to chat .
Okay ?
Jesus ! Watch where you 're going .
Ms. Devlin : Eh , Suzanne .
Come in .
- How are you today ? - Suzanne : Grand .
( dramatic music playing )
( rattling )
Angela : Made you a cup of tea .
Thanks .
How are you feeling today ?
Good .
Uh , this shouldn 't take long .
I actually had all the parts already , so ...
I 'm going for a walk .
If that 's all right ?
I 'm allowed out for a walk , aren 't I ?
Sure , yeah . No , of course .
Uh , the fresh air would be good for you .
Yeah .
( eerie music playing )
- ( indistinct chatter ) - ( birds chirping )
Amanda : Did you even check properly ?
Boy : Yeah , we checked properly .
Hello .
Did you tell someone where we kept those pallets ?
- No . - Kelly : You 're lying .
I 'm not , I saw the council take them away yesterday .
What 's that on your face ?
I asked you a question , Char . What 's that on your face ?
- It 's a birthmark . - Kelly : A birthmark ?
Looks like a burn to me .
Do you want another one ?
Amanda , give me the lighter .
( Kelly chuckling )
Do you want to see something cool ?
- Amanda : Fuckin ' hell , Kelly ! - ( Kelly chuckling )
Kelly : I think you need a reminder
that you 're a little rat .
Right in the middle of your face ,
to make sure you 'll see it
every fucking day .
- ( footsteps approaching ) - ( thudding )
Kelly : What the fuck is wrong with you ?
Fuckin ' bitch .
( dramatic music playing )
Why did you do that ?
Because she deserved it .
You shouldn 't let people treat you like that .
You can 't do that .
Mam ?
Where did you go ...
when you left your car on the green ?
I can 't tell you .
Not yet .
What 's wrong with you ?
Angela : Hey .
Nothing 's wrong .
Everyone 's just trying to tell us what to do .
You and me ...
we can do what we want .
( dramatic music continues playing )
Used to come here with you .
When you were a baby .
Char : Mam , Mam !
Mam !
Mam ! Mam !
( yelps )
( gasps )
What ?
Are you not having fun ?
( eerie music playing )
Rita : Can someone help , please . Aaron , come on . Char !
Char , it 's Aaron !
I need to call an ambulance . Hold his head .
Stay with him .
( gags )
( breathes deeply )
Do you think Aaron 's gonna be okay ?
♪ When God created A woman for me ♪
♪ He must have been In a beautiful mood ... ♪
Mam , what are you doing ?
♪ When he created A woman like you ♪
♪ He made the sun shine Right out of your eyes ... ♪
Dance with me , Char .
No , Mam , stop .
♪ So you could breathe summer Into the air ♪
♪ Oh , me , oh , my You make me sigh ♪
♪ You 're such A good looking woman ♪
- Mam , stop . - ( grunts )
♪ When people stop And people stare ♪
♪ You know it fills My heart with pride ... ♪
Mam !
♪ ... their eyes They 're so surprised ♪
♪ They think you 've fallen Out of ... ♪
- ( grunts ) - Mam , stop ! Mam !
Mam ! Mam , stop ! Stop !
- Stop ! - ( yells )
♪ Who 's walking about With an angel at his side ... ♪
( Angela growling )
- ( bone cracks ) - ( grunts )
( laughs )
( screams )
( pants )
- ( yells ) - Mam , please stop .
- ( grunts ) - Please , stop . Mam !
( growls )
( grunts )
( shrieks )
( ominous music playing )
( Angela growling )
( grunts , sobs )
( tense music playing )
( breathes deeply )
( floorboard creaking )
So , as you all know ,
Samhain is just around the corner .
Or Halloween as we know it now .
Samhain is thought to mean " Summer 's end , "
and is traditionally believed to be the marker
of the start of winter months .
It 's a very special time .
A time when the veil between our world
and the other world was at its thinnest ,
allowing spirits to pass through .
Uh , we still share some traditions
with our ancestors , like bonfires ,
which were traditionally thought
to have protective or cleansing powers .
Anyone here have a bonfire in their area ?
A fellow threw a cat into our bonfire last year .
Well ... ( chuckles )
... okay .
If you follow me through here , we can go to an exhibit
on the practices of early-Christian Ireland
and I can ... I can show you the ... the structures
that they built using those ...
( suspenseful music playing )
Narrator on TV : You are now in a liminal space .
An in-between place .
Why were these sites considered sacred ?
These " thin places "
were seen as a space between our world
and the other world .
In folklore ,
rivers , bogs , lakes , and caves
are often seen as places
where fairy folk could enter the human world .
Or lead humans to theirs .
These sites have been revered and feared throughout time .
Still to this day ,
they are not something we fully understand .
- Kelly : Turn that shite off . - ( projector clicking )
Do you see what your mam did to my eye ?
Have you got nothing to say ?
( exhales deeply ) Yeah .
- You look like shit . - ( Amanda chuckling )
Your crazy bitch of a ma
should be locked up in the mental .
You know , my dad ...
he told me that your whole family
has always been fucking tapped .
Ever since you were born .
He said that when you were a baby ...
your family tried to burn you in a fire .
' Cause they didn 't fucking want you .
Honestly , who could blame them ?
Suzanne : The fuck are you doing , Kelly ?
I 'm joking , Suzanne .
She hasn 't done anything .
Leave her alone .
- Her ma decked Kelly yesterday . - I said leave her alone .
Oh , my God . Suzanne , relax . Okay ?
Fucking hell , we 're only joking .
Weren 't we , Char ?
Whatever . I 'm going for a smoke .
- Are you all right ? - Yeah .
Doctor : How long has your son been on lithium ?
What ... what are you talking about ?
Doctor : Well , we 'll have to wait for his results to come back ,
but it appears your son had a lithium overdose .
What ?
Doctor : Is your son on any medication ?
No . Nothing .
Doctor : Well , I 'd like to keep him in .
For 24 hours at least , just for observation .
His vitals are stable , though his blood pressure has ...
( dramatic music playing )
Suzanne : Do you drink ?
Char : No , I don 't think so .
Suzanne : What are you doing , are you coming ?
Char : Uh , yeah .
( dramatic music playing )
You can 't smoke in here .
Fuck off .
Suzanne : Okay . Inhale . ( chuckles )
Inhale deeper , you want it to go down here .
( coughs )
Suzanne : You have to inhale the second time to ...
Let me show you .
You got it ?
Suzanne : Yes ! Amazing . Amazing .
- ( chuckles ) Congratulations . - ( chuckles ) Thanks .
( distant siren blaring )
I like your necklace .
Thank you . ( chuckles )
My dad got it made for me a few years ago .
It 's a replica of the one my mam was buried in .
I 'm sorry .
I was very young .
I don 't really remember much , so ...
How did she die ?
She drowned .
Char : Oh , my God .
The river , it used to be a lot bigger in this estate .
They tried to build over it , but they couldn 't .
You can still see it underneath .
See ?
She wandered away one night .
And that 's where they found her .
Do you miss her ?
Suzanne : I didn 't really get to know her .
I dream about her sometimes .
Like , she 's watching over me in a way .
( scoffs ) Making sure I 'm not doing something
- too fucking stupid . - ( chuckles )
What about you ?
How 's your mam ?
( dramatic music playing )
Char : When I was younger , she was always
up and down , you know ?
She has these " down days , " Granny calls them .
But I 've never seen her like this .
Just ...
It doesn 't really feel right .
She 's on meds , yeah ?
Yeah .
Well , my dad , he 's been on meds a long time now .
And there 's days where he 's ...
he 's walking around like a zombie .
And then , every now and then , he 's completely himself .
Cracking jokes and ...
( scoffs ) ... I don 't know .
Sometimes , she really ...
scares me .
Family is the scariest fucking thing on the planet .
( chuckles )
You wouldn 't want to come over for dinner tonight ?
Would you ?
- ( chuckles ) Never mind . - No , I would .
Of course , yeah , I would .
I mean , I make an excellent buffer
and , parents , they just hate me .
( both chuckle )
( thudding )
( door opening )
- Rita : Char . - Hi .
Suzanne : Hey .
Rita : Do I know you ?
Yeah , Granny this is Suzanne . She 's in my school .
Suzanne O 'Connell .
Yeah .
Your mother was Adrianne ?
Rita : S ... Suzanne , my dear .
We are having a family dinner tonight ,
and I think it 'd be best if you went home .
Well , Char actually asked me to stay for dinner .
Char : Yeah .
I want her to stay for dinner .
Rita : Can I talk to you in here for a minute ?
Do you want to go and wait in the kitchen ?
- Yeah . - Char : It 's just there .
( muffled chattering )
Delish .
( dramatic music playing )
- Will you do this for me , Char ? - Char : No .
Granny , why ?
I 've asked her to come over for dinner .
She can come another time .
Rita : No , why would she come back another time ,
what 's wrong with today ?
You need to leave .
I 'm asking you and I 've never asked
- can anyone come over before . - ( clattering )
Char : Suzanne ! Suzanne !
Suzanne !
You happy now ?
She 's gone .
- Rita : Char ... - What ?
Rita : There 's things I need to tell you , Char .
Is this about my scar , Granny ?
It 's not a birthmark .
Rita : No .
Your mother was so young ,
when she had you .
It was hard .
But you were such a happy baby .
You never cried .
One night ...
your mother took you out for a walk in the buggy ,
when you couldn 't sleep .
When she came back ...
you weren 't with her .
She couldn 't remember ...
where she 'd been .
We found you down by the river .
You looked perfect .
Still smiling .
We didn 't want to believe ...
it wasn 't you .
What do you mean ?
It was something else .
You were swapped .
What do you mean , Granny ?
To send a changeling back ...
you must bring it to a fire .
You did this to me ?
You know what they all say in school ?
That this family are ... are fucking crazy !
And they 're right .
The ones that took you are vengeful things , Char .
They 've come back for you .
- ( thudding ) - ( breathes shakily )
It 's not your mother up there , Char .
- It 's something else . - Mam ?
You know that 's not your mother , Char .
I know you 've seen it .
- Mam ? Mam ! - No , Char ! Char !
Ch ... Char !
Mam ?
Granny .
Open the door .
If we don 't do something , we 'll never get your mother back
and then they 'll try to take you .
I need you to believe me , Char .
I can 't open that door until you believe me .
( suspenseful music playing )
I believe you .
Rita : Don 't be scared , now .
It might not look like your mother anymore .
She 's started to change .
Rita : We need to weaken her , bring her to a fire .
See if she turns .
Mam ?
Rita : No . No , no , Char . Don 't touch her . No !
- Granny , get off . - Rita : Listen ... listen to me , Char !
- Granny , that 's enough ! - Rita : Char !
( Rita groans )
Ch ... Charlotte . Charlotte !
No , Charlotte . Open the door !
Charlotte , please open the door .
Rita : Are you all right ?
( clattering )
Char , are you all right ?
Char ?
( Angela hisses )
( ominous music playing )
Angela : Open the door .
Open the door , Char .
Rita : Oh , Char .
Angela : I think it 's time we all went to bed .
Granny 's feeling a little bit confused , Char .
I am not confused !
- ( yelling ) - ( thudding )
Char : Mam . Mam !
Mam !
Granny !
Burn it .
( players chattering )
- ( Kelly chuckling ) - ( Amanda chuckling )
Why is he going mad , like ?
Oh , my God , he 's still fighting for it .
( chuckles )
Suzanne : Hey .
Kelly : What are you wearing ?
- A costume . - ( Kelly chuckling )
It 's Halloween , like .
What , is your dad taking you trick or treating ?
Fuck off .
What are youse doing tonight ?
Are you not hanging out with your new little buddy ?
Suzanne : What do you mean ?
Kelly : I don 't know . You tell me .
What 's going on ?
( indistinct chatter )
Kelly : We 're having our own bonfire .
Somewhere where they can 't get it taken down .
We 're going there later .
All right .
Text me , okay ?
Kelly : Amanda !
- Amanda : See you . - See you .
( birds chirping )
( footsteps approaching )
Char : Granny ?
Granny ?
Angela : Char .
( tense music playing )
What happened ?
Angela : Oh , Mam .
Char : Is she dead ?
Angela : I 'll call an ambulance .
- ( phone dialing ) - ( busy tone beeping )
What ?
( doorbell ringing )
Suzanne : Char ?
Char : Hey , what 's up ?
Suzanne : Sorry , I really wanted ...
Mam , I 'm just gonna go over to Suzanne 's for a little bit
if that 's okay ?
I think you should stay here with me .
I want to go .
And what about your granny , Char ?
Char won 't be long , Ms. Delaney .
( suspenseful music playing )
Char !
I think these will fit you .
( clattering )
( bag zipping )
Do you believe me ?
I don 't know what I believe , Char .
But I know you need to leave .
Leave ?
( inhales sharply )
- You can 't stay here . - ( scoffs ) Where would I go ?
I don 't know .
But I 've seen what 's in that house , Char .
You can 't go back .
Char : Granny said that if I don 't do something ...
( shower running )
Char : ... I 'm gonna lose my mam forever .
( dramatic music playing )
She said there was a way to test it .
Suzanne : What do you mean , " Test it " ?
She said ...
that I could bring it to a fire .
( woman cheering )
Are you sure about this ?
Can you get it lighting ?
( laughs )
( kids yelling )
( kids giggle )
( toy witch cackling )
( kids chattering )
- ( Angela yells ) - ( kids scream )
( suspenseful music playing )
Char : Hey !
Are you looking for me ?
( eerie music playing )
Char : Suzanne ?
Suzanne ?
Kelly : You are like a fucking thorn in my side ,
Char Delaney .
I just can 't seem to get fucking rid of you .
- Where 's Suzanne ? - Kelly : Suzanne ?
She said that your whole family were fucking tapped
and she had to get the fuck away from you .
- Speaking of which . - Char : Stop ! Stop !
I think it 's time we finished what your mam started .
- Char : Get off ! - Kelly : Get her in .
- Boy : ( grunts ) Get in . - ( grunts )
( chuckles )
Char : Suzanne !
Suzanne isn 't coming back , Char .
Looks like you 're stuck here with us .
( chuckles )
Give me the aerosol .
- Kelly . - I 'll fucking do it myself .
Amanda : Kelly , you 're not actually doing this ,
are you ?
- ( Kelly chuckling ) - ( lighter clicking )
Amanda : Kelly , stop !
You 're not actually gonna do this ?
Angela : Char ?
- Kelly : What the fuck is that ? - ( kids yell indistinctly )
( suspenseful music playing )
( breathes shakily )
Angela : Look at you .
You 're alone .
No friends .
No family .
You 've nobody left in this world .
( rattling )
Angela : Except me .
You can come with me .
There is a place , where there is no pain .
No sadness .
Don 't you want to see your mother again ?
Oh , she would love to see you .
( tense music playing )
Suzanne : Char !
( fireworks bursting )
Angela : Char .
What are you doing ?
I 'm your mother .
You ...
are not my mother .
( Angela screams )
( shrieks )
( Angela screaming )
Suzanne : Char !
Suzanne : ( muffled ) Run .
( sobs )
Officer : Look , we have no reason to believe
that your sister was in the structure
when the fire broke out .
We 're still trying to figure out what happened .
We searched through the rubble and didn 't find anything .
We haven 't been able to locate her just yet .
Now , uh , Char has been through quite a lot .
Yeah .
So we 'll need to contact the Child and Family Agency .
But don 't worry , you know , we can help you with that .
A social worker will come and make an assessment .
I actually have a ... a contact here .
Um , she 's really good and she 'll be able to help you .
( bell ringing )
( melancholic music playing )
( footsteps approaching )
Hi .
( sobs )
( soft music playing )
( pants ) Are you not meant to be packing boxes ?
Yeah , there 's just a few things I want to keep .
( door knocking )
Hey .
Hmm .
What are you making ?
It 's for protection .
Angela : Thank you .
It 'll keep you safe .
( dramatic music playing )